<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc [
  <!ENTITY nbsp    "&#160;">
  <!ENTITY zwsp   "&#8203;">
  <!ENTITY nbhy   "&#8209;">
  <!ENTITY wj     "&#8288;">
]>
<rfc xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" submissionType="IETF" docName="draft-valentinbinotto-v-verificationsystem-00" category="info" ipr="trust200902" obsoletes="" updates="" xml:lang="en" symRefs="true" sortRefs="false" tocInclude="true" version="3">
  <!-- xml2rfc v2v3 conversion 3.21.0 -->
  <!-- Generated by id2xml 1.5.2 on 2024-06-19T09:14:52Z -->
	<front>
    <title abbrev="V verification system">A method to store information via email and to ensure the verification of the data and the identification of the version</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-valentinbinotto-v-verificationsystem-00"/>
    <author initials="V." surname="Binotto" fullname="Valentin Binotto">
      <organization abbrev="valentin-43-44.org">valentin-43-44.org</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>V434 Project</street>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="June" day="18"/>
    <workgroup>Internet Engineering Task Force</workgroup>
    <abstract>
      <t>
   This document describes a method to store information via email 
   and to ensure the verification of the data and identification of the
   version. As a long-established way of communicating and sharing
   information and knowledge, email is at the heart of the
   V verification system (V-VS).</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <middle>
    <section anchor="sect-1" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Introduction</name>
      <t>
   The permanent storage of information and data is absolutely essential
   for a large proportion of Internet users.
   The name "V verification system" refers to a procedure for sending
   information via email and providing it with defined version
   identification attributes in order to guarantee the subsequent
   traceability of the version history. As this procedure uses the
   existing email infrastructure, elements such as DKIM, SPF or the
   encryption of email content can be used to guarantee the integrity of
   the data.</t>
      <t>
   The V verification system only uses the email infrastructure. This
   means that the use of the V verification system is not associated
   with far-reaching changes to the existing infrastructure, and
   compatibility with legacy infrastructures is guaranteed. Furthermore,
   these minimal requirements mean that the V verification system is
   highly flexible and can also be used in environments with limited
   infrastructure.</t>
      <section anchor="sect-1.1" numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Requirements Language</name>
        <t>
   The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
   "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "NOT RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and
   "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be interpreted as described in
   BCP 14 <xref target="RFC2119" format="default"/> <xref target="RFC8174" format="default"/> when, and only when, they appear in all
   capitals, as shown here.</t>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-2" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>The Specification</name>
      <t>
   The user or administrator who wishes to store data in the sense of
   the V verification system, MUST use their personal individual
   email account (example: valentin@system.valentin).</t>
      <t>
   The user or administrator MUST send the data to a personal,
   individual email address that is also uniquely assigned to them
   (example: valentin@admins.valentin). This address MAY be the same as
   the sender's address, but MAY also be an address that is different
   from the sender's address. The data SHOULD be in the message body of
   the email. The message body itself MAY be formatted as Plain text
   (flat US-ASCII text)([RFC822]) or MIME (<xref target="RFC2045" format="default"/>).</t>
      <t>
   The subject of the email SHOULD include the project name or the name
   of the data to be stored, the current date in the format YYYYMMDD and
   the current time in the format HHMM as well as a random value. The
   subject of an email could therefore look like this:
   "PROJECTXYYZ202406181520 VB"</t>
      <t>
   In order to improve the durability of the data or to enable
   collaboration with other people, these mails MAY also be addressed to
   a mailing list or to various other people in addition to the personal
   email address.</t>
      <t>
   The minimum requirements of the V verification system are described
   in this document. All further details on how the user wishes to use
   the V verification system are the sole responsibility of the user.</t>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-3" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Security Considerations</name>
      <t>
   According to the author, no security considerations apply to this
   document.</t>
    </section>
    <section anchor="sect-4" numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>IANA Considerations</name>
      <t>
   This document has no IANA actions.</t>
    </section>
  </middle>
  <back>
    <references>
      <name>References</name>
      <references>
        <name>Normative References</name>
        <reference anchor="RFC2119" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc2119" xml:base="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Key words for use in RFCs to Indicate Requirement Levels</title>
            <author fullname="S. Bradner" initials="S." surname="Bradner"/>
            <date month="March" year="1997"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>In many standards track documents several words are used to signify the requirements in the specification. These words are often capitalized. This document defines these words as they should be interpreted in IETF documents. This document specifies an Internet Best Current Practices for the Internet Community, and requests discussion and suggestions for improvements.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="14"/>
          <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="2119"/>
          <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC2119"/>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC8174" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc8174" xml:base="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8174.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Ambiguity of Uppercase vs Lowercase in RFC 2119 Key Words</title>
            <author fullname="B. Leiba" initials="B." surname="Leiba"/>
            <date month="May" year="2017"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>RFC 2119 specifies common key words that may be used in protocol specifications. This document aims to reduce the ambiguity by clarifying that only UPPERCASE usage of the key words have the defined special meanings.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="14"/>
          <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="8174"/>
          <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC8174"/>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC5321" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5321" xml:base="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5321.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Simple Mail Transfer Protocol</title>
            <author fullname="J. Klensin" initials="J." surname="Klensin"/>
            <date month="October" year="2008"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This document is a specification of the basic protocol for Internet electronic mail transport. It consolidates, updates, and clarifies several previous documents, making all or parts of most of them obsolete. It covers the SMTP extension mechanisms and best practices for the contemporary Internet, but does not provide details about particular extensions. Although SMTP was designed as a mail transport and delivery protocol, this specification also contains information that is important to its use as a "mail submission" protocol for "split-UA" (User Agent) mail reading systems and mobile environments. [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="5321"/>
          <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC5321"/>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC5322" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5322" xml:base="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.5322.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Internet Message Format</title>
            <author fullname="P. Resnick" initials="P." role="editor" surname="Resnick"/>
            <date month="October" year="2008"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This document specifies the Internet Message Format (IMF), a syntax for text messages that are sent between computer users, within the framework of "electronic mail" messages. This specification is a revision of Request For Comments (RFC) 2822, which itself superseded Request For Comments (RFC) 822, "Standard for the Format of ARPA Internet Text Messages", updating it to reflect current practice and incorporating incremental changes that were specified in other RFCs. [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="5322"/>
          <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC5322"/>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC2045" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc2045" xml:base="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2045.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions (MIME) Part One: Format of Internet Message Bodies</title>
            <author fullname="N. Freed" initials="N." surname="Freed"/>
            <author fullname="N. Borenstein" initials="N." surname="Borenstein"/>
            <date month="November" year="1996"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This initial document specifies the various headers used to describe the structure of MIME messages. [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="2045"/>
          <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC2045"/>
        </reference>
      </references>
      <references>
        <name>Informative References</name>
        <reference anchor="RFC821" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc821" xml:base="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.0821.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Simple Mail Transfer Protocol</title>
            <author fullname="J. Postel" initials="J." surname="Postel"/>
            <date month="August" year="1982"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>The objective of Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP) is to transfer mail reliably and efficiently. SMTP is independent of the particular transmission subsystem and requires only a reliable ordered data stream channel. Obsoletes RFC 788, 780, and 772.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="STD" value="10"/>
          <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="821"/>
          <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC0821"/>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC822" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc822" xml:base="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.0822.xml">
          <front>
            <title>STANDARD FOR THE FORMAT OF ARPA INTERNET TEXT MESSAGES</title>
            <author fullname="D. Crocker" initials="D." surname="Crocker"/>
            <date month="August" year="1982"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This document revises the specifications in RFC 733, in order to serve the needs of the larger and more complex ARPA Internet. Some of RFC 733's features failed to gain adequate acceptance. In order to simplify the standard and the software that follows it, these features have been removed. A different addressing scheme is used, to handle the case of internetwork mail; and the concept of re-transmission has been introduced. Obsoletes RFC 733, NIC 41952.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="STD" value="11"/>
          <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="822"/>
          <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC0822"/>
        </reference>
      </references>
    </references>
  </back>
</rfc>
